Now let's talk about Amazon Kinesis.
So, for the exam,
Kinesis is equal to real-time big data streaming
and it's all you should know.
And I'm going to give you a little bit more information
because there will be not enough, I guess,
for your own understanding.
So Kinesis is as a managed service used to collect, process
and analyze real-time streaming data at any scale.
It's too detailed to know all these things
for the Cloud Practitioner Exam
but still I'm going to give them to you.
It's good to know.
So there's, Kinesis data streams
which is a low latency streaming service to ingest it
at scale from hundreds of thousands of sources
and the source could be whatever can produce data
for example, a truck, a boat, an IOT device
whatever you can think of.
Then you have Kinesis Data Firehose
which is to load these streams
into places that we know already, such as Amazon S3,
Redshift, ElasticSearch, et cetera, et cetera.
We have Kinesis Data Analytics
which is to perform real-time analytics
on the stream using the SQL language.
And finally Kinesis Video Streams
to monitor real-time video streams
for analytics or machine learning.
So at the CCP level, all you need to know
is that Kinesis is used
for real-time big data streaming,
but the sub-services of Kinesis
really line up this way.
So we have Amazon Kinesis streams
that are going to be getting data
from click streams, IOT devices, metrics,
log servers, all these kind of things.
Then we can use Kinesis Data Analytics
if we wanted to analyze this data
and produce output in real-time.
And then we could use Kinesis Firehose
to send these outputs directly into destinations
such as an Amazon S3 buckets
or an Amazon Redshift database
where we can analyze this data
and perform more analytics down the road if we wanted to.
So that's it for Kinesis, I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.